instaproofs.com 2019-04-08

# Sell Photographs Online | Cookies & Privacy | Photo Proofing

Last updated: May 8, 2018

what we collect + how we use it

Instaproofs Privacy Policy

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) describes how we (“Instaproofs”, “we”, “us” or “our”) collect, use, process, and share the information we collect about you. This Privacy Policy applies to information collected on our websites (the “Websites”) which include, but are not limited to: www.instaproofs.com, secure.instaproofs.com, and all other *.instaproofs.com sites. This Privacy Policy also covers any associated content, material, or functionality contained on the Websites or Web Applications (the “Services”).

We encourage you to become familiar with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. By accessing and using any part of our Websites or Services you agree that you have read, understand, and accept the practices described within this Privacy Policy.

Personal Information We Collect

When you browse our Websites, use our Services, contact us by e-mail, make a purchase through our Websites, create an account with us, or otherwise interact with Instaproofs, we may collect personal information about you. The following chart outlines the type of information that we collect, when we collect it, and how we might use it:  

Image Gallery Visitors  
---  
Action | Data Potentially Collected | Why It's Collected  
Gallery Visit | Email Address, Page Visits, Image Views, Links Clicked | Trend analysis, Marketing, Client communications, Abuse prevention, Site personalization  
Photo Added to Favorites | Email Address, Photo Favorited | Site personalization, Buyer-seller communications  
Photo Downloaded | Email Address, IP Address, Photo Downloaded | Site personalization, Buyer-seller communications, Abuse prevention  
Item Added to Cart | Email Address | Site personalization, Buyer-seller communications, Marketing  
Order Placed or Invoice Paid | Contact Info, Shipping Address, IP Address, Payment Details, Items Purchased | Payment processing, Order fulfillment, Buyer-seller communications, Fraud prevention, Marketing  
Contact Email Sent | Contact Info | Buyer-seller communications  
   
Instaproofs' Members (Photographers)  
Action | Data Potentially Collected | Why It's Collected  
Account Creation | Contact Info, Business Name & Location, Business Website URL, Social Media Accounts, Preferences | Client communications, Sending and receiving payments, Abuse prevention, Site personalization, Trend analysis, Marketing  
Logging into Your Account | IP Address, Login Date | Trend analysis, Abuse prevention  
Subscription Payments & Updates | Payment Details, Updates Performed | Payment processing, Account maintenance, Trend analysis  
Order Fulfillment | Contact Info, Shipping Address, IP Address, Payment Details, Items Purchased | Payment processing, Order fulfillment, Buyer-seller communications, Fraud prevention  
Sending Client Emails | Recipient Email Address, Email Subject & Body, Date Emailed | Email delivery, Trend analysis, Abuse prevention  
Emailing Instaproofs Support | Contact Info | Support response and follow-up communications  
3rd Party API Connections | 3rd Party IDs, 3rd Party Names & Details | Payment processing, Order fulfillment, Image Processing, Trend analysis, Abuse prevention  
  
Information Storage Location

We process and store all of the information collected through our Websites and other Services on servers located within the USA.

Information Sharing

We do not sell your personal information. Your personal information is shared only as described below:  

  * With our members (photographers) that have created the photo galleries that you choose to visit and/or purchase from;
  * As is necessary to allow our service providers or agents to provide services for us, such as payment processing, order delivery, and email delivery;
  * As is required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process;
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or property, protect your health and safety or the health and safety of others, investigate fraud or respond to a government request;
  * In connection with a sale of all or substantially all of our assets or the merger of Instaproofs into another entity or any consolidation, share exchange, combination, reorganization, or like transaction in which Instaproofs is not the survivor;
  * As you otherwise request or authorize; and
  * As otherwise permitted or required by law.

We may also share aggregated, non-personally-identifiable data with third party services for trend analysis purposes.

Data Retention Period

We currently retain your personal information for as long as needed in order to provide the Services requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our policies. If you would like your information to be removed before it would generally automatically be removed, you may contact us at [support@instaproofs.com](mailto:support@instaproofs.com) and request for that to happen.

How We Protect Collected Information

We protect your personal information by using commercially reasonable technical and administrative security measures that reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration of your personal information. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and other access authorization controls. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you believe that your information is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of your account has been compromised), please [contact us](mailto:support@instaproofs.com) immediately.

External Service Providers

We work with multiple external service providers to provide a variety of convenient Services to you. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these external service providers' privacy practices and you are encouraged to review the privacy policies of each external service provider individually:  

  * Payment Processing - Payments that are submitted through our Websites are processed by [Stripe](https://stripe.com/). Stripe's privacy policy can be [viewed here](https://stripe.com/us/privacy).
  * Email Services - Emails sent through our Websites are processed by [SendGrid](https://sendgrid.com/). SendGrid's privacy policy can be [viewed here](https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/).
  * Live Chat - Live chat services through our Websites are handled by [PureChat](https://purechat.com/). PureChat's privacy policy can be [viewed here](https://www.purechat.com/privacy).
  * Site Suggestion Tracking - Your provided site suggestions are stored and tracked by [UserVoice](https://uservoice.com/). UserVoice's privacy policy can be [viewed here](https://www.uservoice.com/privacy/).
  * Site Analytics - Site analytics are performed by [Google](https://google.com/). Google's privacy policy can be [viewed here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).
  * Order Fulfillment - We work with multiple print labs to fulfill your print orders, each having their own distinct privacy policy. We encourage you to visit the websites of our lab partners to view their individual privacy policies.

Linked Websites

For your convenience, hyperlinks may be posted on the Website that link to other websites (the “Linked Websites”). Some Linked Websites are not under our control, such as facebook.com, twitter.com, and pinterest.com. We are not responsible for, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to, the privacy practices of any Linked Websites or of any companies that we do not own or control. Linked Websites may collect additional information to that which we collect on the Website. We do not endorse any of these Linked Websites, the services or products described or offered on such Linked Websites, or any of the content contained on the Linked Websites. We encourage you to seek out and read the privacy policy of each website that you visit to understand how Personal Information that is collected about you is used and protected.

Social Media Platforms and Websites

Any information, communications, or material of any type or nature that you submit to any of our pages contained on a social media platform or website by e-mail, posting, messaging, uploading, downloading, or otherwise (collectively, a “Submission”) is done at your own risk and without any expectation of privacy. We cannot control the actions of other users of a social media platform and we are therefore not responsible for any Submissions contained on a social media platform or website. By visiting any of our pages that are contained on any social media platform or website, you are representing and warranting to us that you have reviewed the applicable privacy policy and terms of use of such website or social media platform and that you will abide by all such provisions contained therein.

Sweepstakes, Promotions, Contests & Surveys

You may wish to participate in online polls, surveys, contests, sweepstakes and other promotions (“Optional Activities”) that we may offer through the Website. Participation in these Optional Activities is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to disclose the information required to participate. Information requested may include personal contact information such as your name, address, date of birth, phone number, mobile phone number, e-mail address, username, and/or similar information. We use the information you provide to administer the Optional Activities, contact you or the people you select about the Optional Activities and we may share this information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Under European law, all European citizens have the right to: request a copy of their personal data, have their personal data inaccuracies corrected, have their personal data erased. If you would like to take advantage of any of these options, please email us at [support@instaproofs.com](mailto:support@instaproofs.com).

Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy at any point in the future. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy is reflected by the version date located at the top of this Privacy Policy. All updates and amendments are effective immediately upon notice to you, which we may give by any means, including, but not limited to, by posting a revised version of this Privacy Policy or other notice on the Website. You should review this Privacy Policy often to stay informed of changes that may affect you. Our electronically or otherwise properly stored copies of this Privacy Policy shall each be deemed to be the true, complete, valid, authentic, and enforceable copy of the version of this Privacy Policy.

Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies We Use

We use certain tracking technologies with our system including, without limitation, cookies and local storage within your browser. Please review our Cookie Statement, found below, to understand how we use cookies and how you can control them. We also utilize Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google, in order to better understand your use of our Website and Services. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visits the Website, what pages they visit and what other websites they used prior to visiting. Google uses the data collected to track and examine the use of the Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the data collected on the Website to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Websites is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. Google offers an opt-out mechanism for the web available here.

This Cookie Statement explains how Instaproofs Inc. (“ **Instaproofs** ”, " **we** ", " **us** ", and " **ours** ") use cookies and similar technologies to recognise you when you visit [www.instaproofs.com](https://www.instaproofs.com/) and or any website owned, operated or controlled by us (" **Sites** ").  It explains what these technologies are and why we use them, as well as your rights to control our use of them.

What are cookies?

Cookies are small data files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website.  Cookies are widely used by website owners in order to make their websites work, or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information. 

Cookies set by the website owner (in this case, Instaproofs Inc.) are called "first party cookies".  Cookies set by parties other than the website owner are called "third party cookies".  Third party cookies enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through the website (e.g. like advertising, interactive content and analytics).  The parties that set these third party cookies can recognise your computer both when it visits the website in question and also when it visits certain other websites. 

Why do we use cookies?

We use first party and third party cookies for several reasons. Some cookies are required for technical reasons in order for our Sites to operate, and we refer to these as "essential" or "strictly necessary" cookies. Other cookies also enable us to track and target the preferences of our users to enhance the experience on our Sites.  Third parties serve cookies through our Sites for analytics purposes.  This is described in more detail below.

The specific types of first and third party cookies served through our Sites and the purposes they perform are described in the table below: 

Types of cookies

| 

Who serves  
these cookies

| 

How to refuse  
  
---|---|---  
  
Essential website cookies: These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you with services available through our Sites and to use some of its features, such as access to secure areas. 

| 

Instaproofs

| 

Because these cookies are strictly necessary to deliver the Website to you, you cannot refuse them.

You can block or delete them by changing your browser settings, but doing so may disrupt your viewing experience.  
  
Preference cookies: These cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of our Sites but are non-essential to their use.  However, without these cookies, certain functionality may become unavailable.

| 

Instaproofs

PureChat

UserVoice

TypeKit

| 

You can block or delete these cookies by changing your browser settings.   
  
Analytics and marketing cookies: These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help us understand how our Sites are being used or how effective our marketing campaigns are, or to help us customize our Sites for you.

| 

Instaproofs

Google Analytics

Facebook Analytics

Stripe

| 

You can block or delete these cookies by changing your browser settings. Alternatively,Google offers an opt-out mechanism for the web available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).    
  
How can I control cookies?

You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject cookies. 

You can set or amend your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies. If you choose to reject cookies, you may still use our website though your access to some functionality and areas of our website may be restricted or may not function properly.   As the means by which you can refuse cookies through your web browser controls vary from browser-to-browser, you should visit your browser's help menu for more information.

How often will you update this Cookie Statement?

We may update this Cookie Statement from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to the cookies we use or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.  Please therefore re-visit this Cookie Statement regularly to stay informed about our use of cookies and related technologies. 

The date at the top of this Cookie Statement indicates when it was last updated. 

Where can I get further information?

If you have any questions about our use of cookies or other technologies, please email us at [support@instaproofs.com](mailto:support@instaproofs.com). 

#### Contact details
